[
  {
    "id": "T9A01",
    "correct": 2,
    "question": "What is a beam antenna?",
    "answers": [
      "An antenna built from aluminum I-beams",
      "An omnidirectional antenna invented by Clarence Beam",
      "An antenna that concentrates signals in one direction",
      "An antenna that reverses the phase of received signals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A02",
    "correct": 0,
    "question": "Which of the following describes a type of antenna loading?",
    "answers": [
      "Electrically lengthening by inserting inductors in radiating elements",
      "Inserting a resistor in the radiating portion of the antenna to make it resonant",
      "Installing a spring in the base of a mobile vertical antenna to make it more flexible",
      "Strengthening the radiating elements of a beam antenna to better resist wind damage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A03",
    "correct": 1,
    "question": "Which of the following describes a simple dipole oriented parallel to Earth's surface?",
    "answers": [
      "A ground-wave antenna",
      "A horizontally polarized antenna",
      "A travelling-wave antenna",
      "A vertically polarized antenna"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A04",
    "correct": 0,
    "question": "What is a disadvantage of the short, flexible antenna supplied with most handheld radio transceivers, compared to a full-sized quarter-wave antenna?",
    "answers": [
      "It has low efficiency",
      "It transmits only circularly polarized signals",
      "It is mechanically fragile",
      "All these choices are correct"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A05",
    "correct": 2,
    "question": "Which of the following increases the resonant frequency of a dipole antenna?",
    "answers": [
      "Lengthening it",
      "Inserting coils in series with radiating wires",
      "Shortening it",
      "Adding capacitive loading to the ends of the radiating wires"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A06",
    "correct": 3,
    "question": "Which of the following types of antenna offers the greatest gain?",
    "answers": [
      "5/8 wave vertical",
      "Isotropic",
      "J pole",
      "Yagi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A07",
    "correct": 0,
    "question": "What is a disadvantage of using a handheld VHF transceiver with a flexible antenna inside a vehicle?",
    "answers": [
      "Signal strength is reduced due to the shielding effect of the vehicle",
      "The bandwidth of the antenna will decrease, increasing SWR",
      "The SWR might decrease, decreasing the signal strength",
      "All these choices are correct"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A08",
    "correct": 2,
    "question": "What is the approximate length, in inches, of a quarter-wavelength vertical antenna for 146 MHz?",
    "answers": [
      "112",
      "50",
      "19",
      "12"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A09",
    "correct": 2,
    "question": "What is the approximate length, in inches, of a half-wavelength 6 meter dipole antenna?",
    "answers": [
      "6",
      "50",
      "112",
      "236"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A10",
    "correct": 3,
    "question": "In which direction does a half-wave dipole antenna radiate the strongest signal?",
    "answers": [
      "Equally in all directions",
      "Off the ends of the antenna",
      "In the direction of the feed line",
      "Broadside to the antenna"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A11",
    "correct": 2,
    "question": "What is antenna gain?",
    "answers": [
      "The additional power that is added to the transmitter power",
      "The additional power that is required in the antenna when transmitting on a higher frequency",
      "The increase in signal strength in a specified direction compared to a reference antenna",
      "The increase in impedance on receive or transmit compared to a reference antenna"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T9A12",
    "correct": 0,
    "question": "What is an advantage of a 5/8 wavelength whip antenna for VHF or UHF mobile service?",
    "answers": [
      "It has more gain than a 1/4-wavelength antenna",
      "It radiates at a very high angle",
      "It eliminates distortion caused by reflected signals",
      "It has 10 times the power gain of a 1/4 wavelength whip"
    ]
  }
]